SUMMARY

Lead frontend developer with full stack knowledge. Expertise in Javascript and React.

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

Javascript ES12, Typescript, React, Nextjs, Material UI, Mantine UI, Nodejs, Express, Electron, Webpack, Vite, HTML, CSS, PHP, jQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, JWT, auth0, websockets, NPM, Apache, NGINX, GraphQL, REST API, Git, Notion, Figma, Sublime Text, Visual Studio Code, PuTTY SSH, Wordpress and headless CMS systems, Shopify, Shopify Hydrogen, Liquid, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Amazon AWS, Windows and Linux DevOps, functional and object-oriented programming, AGILE, SCRUM, CICD development (Github Actions), test-driven development (Jest), MVC and component architecture, ChatGPT and Googling.

PROJECTS

2023 – **RES - Simple Booking (Fullstack Web App)** - Online appointment scheduling application for small business owners. Customers can easily schedule an appointment through an interactive online form and the app notifies the owner via text message or email when a new appointment is made. Built with React, Mantine UI, nodejs and MySQL and Amazon SNS.

2022 – <u>realPOS (Fullstack Native App)</u> - Centralized POS software system built with React, nodejs, SQLite and Electron.js packager. It is all made with web technologies but runs natively on the system. It has an easy to use UI/UX for multiple restaurant staff allowing for simple bills, clients and table management.

2022 – **MealPortal (Fullstack Web App)** – Online pickup and delivery ordering software for restaurants. The software sends staff real time order notifications. The software recognizes returning customers through a password-less one-time passcode system that signs a JWT token on verification. It uses Google Maps API Address Autocomplete for 100% correct delivery addresses.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Shopify Web Developer

Dupray Inc., Montreal QC

2022-Present

- Lead the development of the successful web page launch for the Bloom Air Purifier, an award-winning product. This project featured a custom Javascript animation library, creating an interactive user experience that showcased the animated product as the user navigated down the page. This page has generated more than 100K in sales in the first 30 days of launch.
- Deployed multiple scripts interfacing with Shopify REST APIs and GraphQL APIs into production, one of which includes importing all written blog articles spread amongst the 9 stores, sorting them by language and locale, copying interchangeable ones to other stores, sending non-existent ones to be translated via Google Translate API and sending them to be created at their corresponding local store. This created more than 800 missing articles, solving a major SEO HREFLANG issue for the company.
- Lead design and internationalization improvements and integrations throughout the websites in collaboration with in-house Creative Director, Marketing Director, and copywriters. Integrations include Klaviyo, Hotjar, Bazaarvoice.
- Develop business logic for nine international Shopify websites, deployed across three continents.
- Lead the technology revamp for their online store using Shopify Hydrogen, a React framework developed by Shopify.

Full Stack Web Software Developer

MSM Technologies, Montreal QC

2021-2022

- Prototype UI/UX design planning and workflow planning using Figma.
- Develop full stack web applications using React, Nodejs, and MySQL.
- Ensure customer demands are 100% satisfied through regular meetings.
- Perform DevOps provisioning and maintenance on Linux virtual private servers on the cloud.

Assistant Director Mitsuki DIX30, Brossard QC 2020-2021

- Mounted Raspberry Pi digital signage menu displays.
- Developed a full stack web application for online ordering and the static restaurant business website.

Freelance 2015-2020

Create web applications and static websites for small to medium businesses.

EDUCATION

AEC Linux and Windows Network Administration	Édouard Montpetit CÉGEP, Longueuil QC	2022-Present
Studies in Bachelor of Accountancy	Concordia University, Montreal QC	2016